<?xml version="1.0" ?> <article xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
   <header>
      <title>HIV Prevention for Men Who Have Sex With Men</title>
      <categories>
         <category_item>health</category_item>
         <category_item>HIV/AIDS</category_item>
         <category_item>freelance translantion</category_item>
         <category_item>translation</category_item>
      </categories>
      <autor>Gloria Edini</autor >
   </header>
   <content><![CDATA[
   
   <p>
   Script for: HIV Prevention for Men Who Have Sex With Men.<br>
Hi, my name is [PRESENTER NAME]. I’m [PRESENTER ROLE]. Welcome to “HIV Prevention for Men Who Have 
Sex With Men.” This video discusses how you can reduce your risk of contracting HIV, the virus that 
causes AIDS. It will teach you information that can save your life and the life of any current or 
future sexual partner, so please listen carefully and watch the whole video. 
You are probably aware that HIV is present in some body fluids including blood and semen and is 
most commonly transmitted through sexual contact. HIV spreads when one person’s body fluids such 
as blood or semen come in direct contact with another person’s mucous membranes or breaks in the 
skin. Examples of mucous membranes include the eyes, nose, mouth, anus and genitals.
It’s important to realize that a person can be infected with HIV and not even know it. It can take up to six months after being infected with HIV for ordinary tests to show that you are HIV positive. After a person has contracted HIV, even before they test positive, it’s possible for them to pass on the infection to others. So don’t assume your partner is HIV negative just because they look healthy.
What are your options to reduce or eliminate your risk of contracting HIV?
Some men choose to abstain from sexual activity or coose to be mutually faithful to one partner. Other men take steps to reduce their risk of contracting HIV by using a condom with each partner.
It’s critical to use a latex condom correctly every time you have sex, every way you have sex. A latex condom is not a guarantee against HIV transmission, but when used correctly, it greatly reduces the risk that one partner will infect the other. 
For a condom to provide the best protection against HIV, you must use it correctly.  Condoms must be stored in a cool, dark place. Do not expose them to oil-based lubricants like Vaseline, because they will weaken the condom. To use a condom correctly, you must put it on the hard penis before any contact between the penis and the partner’s mouth or anus. When putting the condom on the penis, leave a little extra space at the tip to hold the semen, and unroll the condom down the shaft all the way.  After the man ejaculates, he should hold the condom at the base of his shaft to make sure it doesn’t fall off and immediately remove his penis from his partner before the penis becomes soft. This will reduce the risk that the condom will leak. Afterwards, throw the condom away. 
Another video on this web site demonstrates how to correctly use a condom.
Make sure that both you and your partner know your HIV status. A simple, quick blood test or oral sample where they take a swab of the inside of your mouth, can tell you whether you are HIV positive. In most countries, this test is available free of charge. Remember that it can take up to six months after being exposed to HIV for your HIV test to turn positive, so you only know for sure that you are HIV negative if you have tested negative for HIV six months after your last possible exposure to HIV.
The more sexual partners you have, the greater your risk of contracting HIV. Reducing your number 
of sexual partners can also dramatically reduce your risk of contracting HIV. 
No matter who you are, you are a valuable individual, and your life matters as do the lives of 
those in your community. Take care of yourself and those around you. Make healthy choices that eliminate or reduce your risk of contracting HIV. This is [PRESENTER NAME].
Script by Becky Kuhn, M.D. of Global Lifeworks and Eric Krock of AIDSvideos.org.
This script was reviewed for accuracy and approved by Becky Kuhn, M.D. on April 22, 2007.
</p>

   
   
   ]]>
   </content>
</article>