<?xml version="1.0" ?> <article xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
   <header>
      <title>TRANSLATION _ HIV/AIDS Introductory</title>
      <categories>
         <category_item>translation</category_item>
      </categories>
   </header>
   <content><![CDATA[
      <ul>
      	<li><strong>Introduction to HIV/AIDS</strong></li>
      </ul>
      Free translation achieved from the english HIV/AIDS articles to portuguese language:<br/><br/><strong>Introduction to HIV/AIDS:
      What You Need to Know  </strong><br/><br/>Translation into the Portuguese language from the english original article <em><span
      class="videotitle">Introduction to HIV and AIDS: What You Need to Know</span></em>. It was  achieved in contribution with
      the works of the Eric Krock <a href="http://www.aidsvideos.org/">IDSvideo.org</a>., as part of the serie of scripts for elaboration
      of videos on HIV/AIDS.  This first article  entittled in portuguese as <strong>Introdução ao HIV_AIDS</strong> is already
      edited on <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-3OiM31t2mE">vídeo</a>.
      <ul>
      	<li><strong>HIV/AIDS "Better Adherence for a Better Life"</strong></li>
      </ul>
      Free translation to Portuguese language from script “Better Adherence for a Better Life!”.  This work was achieved in contribution
      with Eric Krock <a href="http://www.aidsvideos.org/">IDSvideo.org</a>. This article  clarifies why it's so important for HIV
      positive people to take their antiretroviral medications (ARVs).<br/><br/>It also talks about the importance of the prescribed
      schedules. The article directions represent a dialog between the position of the infected person and his adhesion to a program
      of health that can always bring him a condition of healthy life.  The Portuguese version is named  "Melhor aderência para
      uma vida melhor".<br/><br/>See: <a href="http://aidsvideos.org/translate.shtml">http://aidsvideos.org/translate.shtml</a>
      <ul>
      	<li><strong>HIV and AIDS: Prevention for Positives</strong></li>
      </ul>
      Text translation of the English original " HIV and AIDS_Prevention will be Make positive " of the  AIDSvideos.org.translation
      series. The article brings important informations for positives as how to keep on living with health,  get a better life,
      and make possible that disease does not continue doing victims. Proceedings, risks, and helping are also contents of this
      article.  See articles http: // aidsvideos.org/translate.shtml
      <ul>
      	<li> <strong>Crystal Methamphetamine and HIV: The Connection.</strong>
      translation english/portuguese_ptbr</li>
      </ul>
      Translation achieved to the Portuguese language intitled  “Cristal de Metanfetamina e HIV: A Conexão.” The article discuss
      the history of crystal methamphetamine and its impact on the spread of HIV/AIDS.  It clarifies why the Crystal causes so destruction
      in the human body, its effetcs on the brain, how it can increase the spreading of HIV, and how to get treatment program. See
      articles http: // aidsvideos.org/translate.shtml
      <ul>
      	<li><strong>Did I Just Contract HIV? Symptoms of Primary HIV Infection.</strong></li>
      </ul>
      <ul></ul>
      Translation into the Portuguese language from the english original article "Did I Just Contract HIV?" The matter is how is
      possible to recognize when a person recently contracted HIV . This translation is a script for a  video that will teach people
      how to recognize signs and symptoms of primary HIV infection. See articles http: // aidsvideos.org/translate.shtml]]>
   </content>
</article>