<?xml version="1.0" ?> <article xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
   <header>
      <title>Preventing Mother-to-Child Transmission of HIV/AIDS in Developed Countries: What 
You Need to Know</title>
      <categories>
         <category_item>health</category_item>
         <category_item>HIV/AIDS</category_item>
         <category_item>freelance translantion</category_item>
         <category_item>translation</category_item>
      </categories>
      <autor>Gloria Edini</autor >
   </header>
   <content><![CDATA[
<p>
If a woman is HIV positive and becomes pregnant, there is a risk that her child will 
contract HIV during the pregnancy, more commonly during childbirth or while 
breastfeeding. If an HIV positive woman takes no steps to protect her child from HIV 
and does not breastfeed, there is a 15-30% chance that her child will contract HIV. If 
she also breastfeeds, the risk of transmission increases to 20-45%.
However, if an HIV positive woman follows her doctor's instructions, which will 
include use of appropriate antiretroviral medications, it is possible to reduce the risk of 
the child contracting HIV. If you are pregnant or thinking about having a baby, the 
information in this video could save your child's life, so please watch the whole video 
and listen carefully.<br>

This video is intended for women who are in developed nations such as the United 
States and Western Europe. Women in these countries who are HIV positive can 
usually get access to medical treatment they need to decrease mother-to-child 
transmission of HIV. There is a separate video on this site for women in developing 
countries who may not have access to health care services or medications.<br>

See a Doctor<br>

If you know you are pregnant or are thinking about having a baby, see a doctor. They 
can give you health advice that will maximize your chances for a safe pregnancy and a 
healthy baby whether or not you have HIV.<br>

Get Tested for HIV<br>

The next step to protecting your baby from HIV/AIDS is to get tested and find out if 
you are HIV positive. You may be HIV positive and not know it. The U.S. Public 
Health Service recommends that all pregnant women be tested for HIV and even that 
HIV testing become part of a routine medical check-up.<br>

Even if you are already well along in your pregnancy or nearing delivery, you should 
still be tested for HIV, if you had not been tested before. The sooner you are tested, the 
better your chances of protecting your child from HIV, so don't delay. You can't 
protect your child if you don't know your HIV status.<br>

In most countries this test is available free of charge.<br>
If You're HIV Negative, Stay That Way<br>
If you are pregnant and have tested HIV negative, you can reduce your risk of 
becoming positive during your pregnancy by staying mutually faithful to one partner or 
using condoms.   Pregnant women need to be just as careful as anyone else to avoid 
contracting HIV.<br>

If You're HIV Positive, See a Doctor Right Away<br>
If you are HIV positive, do not despair. With modern antiretroviral medications, it is 
now possible for HIV positive individuals to remain healthy for years, even decades. If 
you are pregnant and follow your doctor's instructions, you can also reduce your 
child's chance of contracting HIV. <br>

The rest of this video will tell you about some of the steps your doctor may recommend 
to protect your infant if you are pregnant. Remember, different people have different 
needs, and watching a video is no substitute for seeing a doctor and getting personal 
advice that's right for you.<br>

Antiretroviral Medications (ARVs)<br>

HIV is a virus. Antiretroviral Medications known as ARVs can interfere with the 
virus's ability to reproduce and infect new cells within your body. Your doctor will 
suggest using ARVs to protect your baby.<br>

Starting ARVs Immediately<br>

Your doctor may recommend that you start taking antiretroviral medications 
immediately if you are not already on them. Your doctor is especially likely to 
recommend this if you are showing symptoms of clinical AIDS, your T cell count 
(immune cells) is low, or the amount of virus in your body is high. Going on ARVs can 
improve your own health as well as reducing the chance that your child will contract 
HIV during pregnancy, or, more commonly, during childbirth.  If you are already on 
ARVs, your doctor will keep you on them, except for Sustiva, which has been shown to 
cause problems for a developing fetus. If your doctor prescribes ARVs, it's extremely 
important to take every dose of the medications on schedule. A separate video on this 
web site called "Prevention for Positives" explains more about why taking every dose 
of ARV medications on schedule is so important.<br>

Starting ARVs After the First Trimester<br>

Even if your doctor doesn't recommend that you start ARVs immediately, they will 
recommend going on ARVs after the first trimester.  The reason for this is to minimize 
the effects of ARVs on a fetus while they are in the most critical early development 
stages in the womb.  Many studies have been done on the safety of ARVs during 
pregnancy, so protect the health of your baby by taking ARVs according to your 
doctor's instructions. <br>

Scheduled Caesarian Section<br>

There is evidence that the risk of mother-to-child HIV transmission may be lower if the 
child is delivered via a scheduled Caesarian section rather than by a natural vaginal 
delivery.  Additionally, if a woman is on ARV and her viral load Ð or amount of virus 
in the body is less than 1,000, vaginal delivery is as low a risk as Caesarian section Ð 
approximately 1%. Of course, Caesarian sections carry their own increased risks of 
infection for the mother and possible respiratory complications for the child. Talk with 
your doctor as early in your pregnancy as possible about what the best approach may be 
for your situation.<br>

Intravenous (IV) ARVs During Labor and Delivery<br>
In standard medical practice, every HIV positive woman should receive IV AZT during 
delivery, once her water has broken.  <br>

ARVs for the Child After Delivery<br>
It is possible to further reduce the risk that the baby will become HIV positive by 
giving the infant oral antiretroviral medications after delivery. The U.S. Public Health 
Service recommends that babies born to HIV positive mothers be given AZT in liquid 
form every 6 hours for six weeks after birth and it's critical that you give the child 
every dose of medication on schedule.<br>

Feeding the Child Formula Instead of Breastfeeding<br>
 If the mother is HIV positive and breastfeeds her baby, this increases the risk of 
mother-to-child HIV transmission. As a result, if the mother is HIV positive, "The CDC 
recommends that in areas where safe drinking water and infant formula are available 
(such as the United States), [HIV positive] women should not breastfeed in order to 
avoid transmission of HIV to their infants through breast milk."<br>

Testing the Baby for HIV<br>
All babies born to HIV positive mothers should be tested to determine whether they are 
HIV positive. "Babies born to HIV positive mothers are tested for HIV differently than 
adults. Adults are tested by looking for antibodies to HIV in their blood. A newly born 
infant keeps antibodies from its mother, including antibodies to HIV, for many months 
after birth. Therefore, an antibody test given before the baby is 1 year old may be 
positive even if the baby does NOT have HIV infection. For the first year, babies are 
tested for HIV directly, and not by looking for antibodies to HIV. When babies are 
more than 1 year old, they no longer have their mother's antibodies and can be tested 
for HIV using the antibody test.  If after 1 year, the baby tests negative, they are 
considered HIV negative.<br>

If Your Child is HIV Positive<br>
If your child turns out to be HIV positive, do not despair. Talk with your doctor about 
what treatments are right for your child. With appropriate treatment, HIV positive 
infants may be able to live a healthy life. There are already college students today who 
were born as HIV positive infants. If your child is HIV positive, talk with your doctor 
about how to keep them healthy and make sure to follow the doctor's instructions 
exactly.<br>

Important Things to Remember<br>
Let's close by reviewing some of the most important lessons from this video.
¥	If you are suspect you are pregnant or want to become pregnant, see a doctor and get 
tested to determine if you are HIV positive.<br>
¥	If you are pregnant and HIV positive, there are many things you can do to reduce the 
risk of mother-to-child transmission. It's important that you talk to your doctor about 
what to do to keep the risk as low as possible and follow the doctor's instructions 
exactly.<br>

For AIDSvideos.org, this is [PRESENTER NAME].<br>

Script written by Becky Kuhn, M.D. of Global Lifeworks and Eric Krock of 
AIDSvideos.org.<br>
This script was reviewed for accuracy and approved by Becky Kuhn, M.D. on August 
29, 2006.<br>
</p>
]]>
   </content>
</article>
 

