 <?xml version="1.0" ?> <article xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
   <header>
      <title>Share page</title>
      <categories>
         <category_item>sharing</category_item>
         </categories>
      <autor>Gloria Edini</autor>
   </header>
   <content><![CDATA[

   <h2>Literature page</h2>
   
   <p>
   Share space to comments of literary works, poems, photos .. so, it's a open space for reality 
   and imaginary  things, where all ideas will be wellcome.
   </p>
   
   <h2> Share Information</h2>
   <p>
   In this page there is a space for share information, exchanging experiences, expressions and all
   kinds that you want to know. ok?
   </p>
   
   <blockquote>
   “If you have an apple and I have an apple, and we exchange these apples then you and I will 
   still each have one apple. But if you have an idea and I have an idea, and we exchange these 
   ideas, then each of us will have two ideas.<br>
   
   George Bernard Shaw</blockquote>
   
   <p>
   The translation <br>
   
   I know translating is an art. The professor Brenno Silveira talks in his book <em>The art of 
   translation </em>that translating is all, except sample. I have seen that it’s really, - all 
   is able, but not sample! This work has two segments, both with expression and content plans 
   that must be well defined.<br>
   
   In the first segment, the translator need to be loyal to the document and to the author. 
   He need respects the authorship as so to find in the new language the linguisstic elements,
   as near as possible, to translate the ideas of the author.<br>
   
   About Web texts sometimes is necessary to get a few knowlodges about the article whose you are 
   working, for example, testing installation, trying options, or to see how it works. 
   Is important to have a link between the autor with translator, or about technical text is 
   important the translator understanding the subject that will be translate.
   </p>
      
      ]]>
   </content>
</article>