<?xml version="1.0" ?> <article xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
   <header>
      <title>freelance translation: HIV/AIDS</title>
      <categories>
         <category_item>health</category_item>
         <category_item>translations</category_item>
         <category_item>HIV/AIDS</category_item>
       </categories>
      <autor>Gloria Edini</autor >
   </header>
   <content><![CDATA[
   	<h2>Introduction to HIV/AIDS</h2>
      
    <p>  Free translation achieved from the english HIV/AIDS articles to portuguese language:
 These translations were made with permission of <a href="http://aidsvideos.org/translate.shtml".
 </p>
  
  Article:<br>
  <ul>
  <li>Script (en) “HIV and AIDS_Prevention for Positives” (ptBR) "HIV e AIDS_Prevenção para
      	Soro-positivos."
  </li>
  </ul>
   <p>Text translation from the English original " HIV and AIDS_Prevention will be make positive " 
      of the  AIDSvideos.org.translation
      series. The article brings important informations for positives as how to keep on living 
      with health,  get a better life,
      and make possible that disease does not continue doing victims. Proceedings, risks, and 
      helping are also contents of this
      article.  See articles http: // aidsvideos.org/translate.shtml.
  </p>
      
      
  Article:<br>
  <ul>
  <li>
  Script (en) “Better Adherence for a Better Life!" (ptBR)"Melhor aderência para uma vida melhor".
   </li>
   </ul>
   <p>
      Free translation to Portuguese language from script “Better Adherence for a Better Life!”.  
     This work was achieved in contribution
      with Eric Krock <a href="http://www.aidsvideos.org/">IDSvideo.org</a>. 
      This article  clarifies why it's so important for HIV
      positive people to take their antiretroviral medications (ARVs).<br>
      It also talks about the importance of the prescribed
      schedules. The article directions represent a dialog between the position of the infected 
      person and his adhesion to a program 
      of health that can always bring him a condition of healthy life.  The Portuguese version 
      is named  "Melhor aderência para
      uma vida melhor".<br>
      See: <a href="http://aidsvideos.org/translate.shtml">http://aidsvideos.org/translate.shtml</a>
  </p>    
     
      	
 Article:<br>
 <ul>
 <li>
     Script (en) “HIV and AIDS_Prevention for Positives” (ptBR) "HIV e AIDS_Prevenção para 
      Soro-positivos".
 </li>
 </ul>     
  <p>
  
  </p>
  
  Article:<br>
  <ul>
  <li>
     Script (en) “Crystal Methamphetamine and HIV: The Connection.” (ptBR) “Cristal de 
      Metanfetamina e HIV: A Conexão".
   </li>
   </ul>
   <p>
      Translation achieved to the Portuguese language intitled  “Cristal de Metanfetamina e HIV: 
      A Conexão.” The article discuss
      the history of crystal methamphetamine and its impact on the spread of HIV/AIDS.  It clarifies 
      why the Crystal causes so destruction
      in the human body, its effetcs on the brain, how it can increase the spreading of HIV, and 
      how to get treatment program. See
      articles http://www.aidsvideos.org/translate.shtml.
    </p>
    
    Article:<br>
  <ul>
  <li>
     Script (en) “Did I Just Contract HIV? Symptoms of Primary HIV Infection.” (ptBR) “Eu 
      contraí o HIV? Sintomas primários de infecção do HIV".
  </li>
  </ul>
  <p>
      Translation into the Portuguese language from the english original article "Did I Just 
      Contract HIV?" The matter is how is
      possible to recognize when a person recently contracted HIV . This translation is a script 
      for a  video that will teach people
      how to recognize signs and symptoms of primary HIV infection. 
      See articles http: // aidsvideos.org/translate.shtml
   </p>
   
   Article:<br>
   <ul>
   <li>
      Script (en) “HIV - Prevention for Men who have sex with men”. (ptBR) "HIV - Prevenção 
      para Homens que fazem sexo com homens".
   </li>
   </ul>   
   <p>
   
   </p>
   
   Article:<br>
   <ul>
   <li>
       Script (en) “Introduction to HIV/AIDS: What You Need to Know”. (ptBR) (ptBR)"Introdução ao HIV 
       e AIDS: O que você precisa saber".
   </li>
   </ul>
   <p>
      Translation into the Portuguese language from the english original article <em><span
      class="videotitle">Introduction to HIV and AIDS: What You Need to Know</span></em>. 
      It was  achieved in contribution with
      the works of the Eric Krock <a href="http://www.aidsvideos.org/">IDSvideo.org</a>, as part of 
      the serie of scripts for elaboration
      of videos on HIV/AIDS.  This first article  entittled in portuguese as <strong>Introdução ao 
      HIV_AIDS</strong> is already
      edited on <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-3OiM31t2mE">vídeo</a>.
   </p>
   
   Article:<br>
   <ul>
   <li>
       Script (en) "The Top 10 Myths About HIV and AIDS”. (ptBR)
   </li>
      
   <li> Script (en) “Preventing Mother-to-Child Transmission of HIV/AIDS in Developed Countries: 
        What You Need to Know” (ptBR). “Prevenção à transmissão do HIV/AIDS de mãe para filho em 
        países desenvolvidos: O que você precisa saber”. (ptBR)
   </li>
      
   <li> Script (en) “Preventing Mother-to-Child Transmission of HIV/AIDS in Developing Countries: 
        What You Need to Know” (ptBR) “Prevenção à transmissão do HIV/AIDS de mãe-para-filho em países 
        em desenvolvimento: O que você precisa saber”.
   </li>
      
   <li> Script (en) “Why EVERY Person Should Be Tested for HIV When They Visit the Doctor”.
        (ptBR) “Why EVERY Person Should Be Tested for HIV When They Visit the Doctor”.
   </li>
      
   <li> Script (en) “Wash Your Hands to Keep Yourself and Others Healthy: Recommendations 
        for the Developed World". (ptBR) “Lave suas mãos para preservar a sua saúde e a dos outros: 
        recomendações para o mundo desenvolvido".
   </li>
      
   <li> Script (en) “Wash Your Hands to Keep Yourself and Others Healthy: Recommendations 
        for the Developing World". (ptBR) “Lave suas mãos para preservar a sua saúde e a dos outros: 
        recomendações para o mundo em desenvolvimento".
   </li>
      
   <li> Script (en) “Preventing Waterborne Illnesses – the Major Cause of Death in 
        Developing Countries”. (ptBR) “Prevenindo doenças de veiculação hídrica – a maior causa de 
        morte em países em desenvolvimento”(ptBR)
   </li>
      
   <li> Script (en) "Preventing Sexual Transmission of HIV: What You Need to Know". (ptBR) 
        Prevenção de transmissão sexual do HIV: O que você precisa saber". 
    </li>
      
    </ul>
      
   ]]>
   </content>
</article>


 
     
     
    
  



