<?xml version="1.0" ?> <article xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
   <header>
      <title>HIV and AIDS: Prevention for Positives</title>
      <categories>
         <category_item>health</category_item>
         <category_item>HIV/AIDS</category_item>
         <category_item>freelance translantion</category_item>
         <category_item>translation</category_item>
      </categories>
      <autor>Gloria Edini</autor >
   </header>
   <content><![CDATA[
      <p>
 Welcome to the “HIV and AIDS: Prevention for Positives.” This video is intended for individuals 
 who are HIV positive and their partners and will explain how to reduce your risk of transmitting 
 or contracting HIV.<br>

 HIV is a 100% preventable illness. It is important to remember that we all have the opportunity 
 to help stop the spread of this deadly virus. If you are HIV negative, it is important to remember 
 how HIV is transmitted and minimize your risk of contracting it through abstinence, being mutually 
 faithful to one partner, using a condom for every sexual activity including oral, genital, and 
 anal, and for those who inject drugs, not sharing needles. Obviously, if you are in a culture 
 where you do not have equal rights, you may not be able to follow these guidelines.<br>

 Knowing your HIV status is the first step in making sure that you will never spread it. The U.S. 
 government has even suggested that HIV testing be a part of a regular medical check-up. No matter 
 who you are, if you do not know your HIV status, please get tested. You can either be tested 
 confidentially or anonymously. Testing confidentially means that only you and your health care 
 provider will know your name and test result. In the United States and many other countries, 
 there are strong laws that protect the confidentiality of information between the health care 
 provider and their patients. If you are concerned about confidentiality, in many places you can 
 test anonymously. In anonymous testing, you do not disclose your name. You can contact your local 
 health department for testing and if they do not offer it onsite, they will direct you to the 
 nearest location.<br>

 If you are HIV positive, you have the opportunity to make sure that HIV stops with you. Many 
 of my patients have told me they do not feel safe telling their partners about their HIV status 
 because they are afraid of being rejected. I can only imagine what it would be like to experience 
 that fear. When you know your HIV status but don’t disclose it, you may be carrying a burden. 
 You have the chance to set that burden down. By taking a stand to disclose your status to every 
 potential partner, you create a freedom of choice that did not previously exist. You may be 
 saying to yourself, “I was not given that freedom of choice when I contracted HIV, why should 
 I give that freedom to someone else?” You may not have had the knowledge at the time you 
 contracted HIV. However, you now have the power to make sure that HIV stops with you. That may 
 be the only power you feel like you have over your life at this time, and it is a good place to 
 start. Make the decision today to let HIV stop with you.<br>

 Another opportunity to have HIV stop with you is a suggestion from the Centers for Disease Control 
 and Prevention. They recommend that all newly diagnosed HIV positive individuals voluntarily 
 provide the names and contact details of all previous sexual partners to the local public health 
 services. The list of partners includes both those who may have infected you and those you may 
 have exposed to HIV. This notification creates the opportunity for the partners to receive 
 counseling and testing for HIV. Participation in this program is entirely voluntary, and you 
 can make the decision after you get your test results. You will never be required to provide 
 the names of past sexual partners if you don’t want to.<br>

 I am often asked if there are any increased risks for two HIV infected individuals having 
 unprotected sex or sharing needles. This has been called serosorting – HIV positive individuals 
 having HIV positive sexual partners instead of HIV negative partners in order to prevent further 
 spread of HIV. My answer is not very popular and sometimes not very well received. While the 
 intention of serosorting may be good, preventing HIV negative individuals from contracting HIV, 
 the science does not support this practice as completely safe. There are many strains of the HIV 
 virus and any one individual may be carrying a different strain than their partner. In addition, 
 over time the HIV virus has been exposed to a number of different medications and has developed 
 resistance – it has mutated or changed its shape so that those medications and possibly others 
 in the same class or group are no longer effective.<br>

 When two HIV positive individuals exchange body fluids through unprotected sex or needle sharing, 
 they run the risk of acquiring each other’s virus. This is called superinfection. Since this is 
 not a common occurrence, some individuals feel there is not enough evidence to warrant using 
 condoms, even if both partners are HIV positive. Nonetheless, if you acquire another strain of 
 HIV through a risky behavior, the odds are 100% for you. Physicians have seen the effects of 
 superinfection on a patient’s CD4 count. For example, one patient’s CD4 count had been stable 
 for many many years. After an unprotected sexual encounter with another man in a foreign country, 
 he developed a significant drop in his CD4 count and it never recovered.<br>

 Another way to increase the chances that HIV stops with you is, if you are on antiretroviral 
 medications, to take them at the dosages and on schedule as prescribed by your physician. When 
 you take your medications as prescribed, you accomplish two things. You reduce the risk of 
 developing resistance to the HIV virus. Secondly, you reduce the amount of virus in your body, 
 called your viral load, hopefully to a nondetectable level. A lower viral load decreases your 
 chance of transmitting HIV. Taking your medications as prescribed, however, is no substitute 
 for safer sexual practices.<br>

 Another way to increase the chance that HIV stops with you is to make sure that you and your 
 partner are healthy and do not have other sexually transmitted diseases. Studies have shown that 
 having other sexually transmitted diseases at the time when you are having unprotected sex 
 increases the risk of both transmitting and of contracting HIV. Being free of other sexually 
 transmitted diseases, however, is no substitute for safer sexual practices. Barriers such as 
 condoms and dental dams are always a necessary part of safer sex.<br>

 No matter who you are, you are a valuable individual, and your life matters as do the lives 
 of those in your community. Take care of yourself and those around you. Make healthy choices 
 that eliminate or reduce your risk of contracting HIV.<br>

 For AIDSvideos.org, this is [PRESENTER NAME].<br>
 </p>]]>
   </content>
</article>
 