<?xml version="1.0" ?> <article xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
   <header>
      <title>résumé</title>
      <categories>
         <category_item>Uncategorized</category_item>
      </categories>
   </header>
   <content><![CDATA[
      <ul>
      	<li><strong> TEXT ORGANIZATION </strong></li>
      </ul>
      Activities achieved as text organization in the following english Web documentations:<br/><br/>PinkPaula V2 for <a href="http://www.pinktheme.com/en/themes/pinkpaula/">Fx
      2</a> and  IE<br/><br/><a href="http://www.pinktheme.com/en/cs/searchstyle/">SearchStyle </a><br/><br/><a href="http://www.pinktheme.com/en/cs/searchstyle/custom.html">SearchStyle
      Custom</a><br/><br/><a href="http://www.pinktheme.com/en/cs/searchstyle/results.html">Page of Results</a><br/><br/>PinkTabs
      <ul>
      	<li><strong>WEB TRANSLATION</strong></li>
      </ul>
      Translations achieved from the english Web documentations to the following languages:<br/><br/>Pink Paula V2<strong>: </strong><br/><br/>to
      the languages:  <a href="http://www.pinktheme.com/pt-br/themes/pinkpaula/">portuguese</a>,   <a href="http://www.pinktheme.com/fr/themes/pinkpaula/">francese</a>,
      <a href="http://www.pinktheme.com/es/themes/pinkpaula/">spanish</a><br/><br/>SearchStyle:<br/><br/>to  <a href="http://www.pinktheme.com/pt-br/cs/searchstyle/">portuguese</a>
      and   <a href="http://www.pinktheme.com/fr/cs/searchstyle/">francese</a><br/><br/>SearchStyle Custom:<br/><br/>to  <a href="http://www.pinktheme.com/fr/cs/searchstyle/custom.html">francese</a>
      and  <a href="http://www.pinktheme.com/pt-br/cs/searchstyle/custom.html">portuguese</a><br/><br/>Page of Results<br/><br/>to
      <a href="http://www.pinktheme.com/fr/cs/searchstyle/results.html">francês</a>,  and <a href="http://www.pinktheme.com/pt-br/cs/searchstyle/results.html">português</a><br/><br/>PinkTabs:<br/><br/>to
      portuguese, francese, and spanish.
      <ul>
      	<li><strong>LITERATURE PAGE</strong>: <a href="http://gloria.taboca.com/">Real and Imaginary</a></li>
      </ul>
      Share space to comments of literary works, poems, photos .. so, it's a open space for reality and imaginary  things, where
      all ideas will be wellcome.
      <ul>
      	<li> <strong>ON HIV/AIDS INTRODUCTORY</strong></li>
      </ul>
      Translations achieved as freelance translator of scripts to date into Portuguese  for  http://aidsvideos.org/translate.shtml
      with the following scripts:
      <ul>
      	<li>script “Better Adherence for a Better Life!" "Melhor aderência para uma vida melhor."</li>
      	<li>script “HIV and AIDS_Prevention for Positives” "HIV e AIDS_Prevenção para Soro-positivos."</li>
      	<li>script “Crystal Methamphetamine and HIV: The Connection.” “Cristal de Metanfetamina e HIV: A Conexão.</li>
      	<li> script “Did I Just Contract HIV? Symptoms of Primary HIV Infection.” “Eu contraí o HIV? Sintomas primários de infecção
      do HIV"</li>
      	<li> script “HIV - Prevention for Men who have sex with men”. (en). "HIV - Prevenção para Homens que fazem sexo com homens".(ptBR)</li>
      	<li> <span class="vtitle">"Introdução ao HIV e AIDS: O que você precisa saber</span>" v. versão <a href="http://www.videospider.tv/Videos/Detail/955949978.aspx">pt-br</a></li>
      	<li> 'The Top 10 Myths About HIV and AIDS”</li>
      	<li> “Preventing Mother-to-Child Transmission of HIV/AIDS in Developed Countries: What You Need to Know”(en). “Prevenção
      da Transmissão do HIV/AIDS de Mãe para Filho em Países Desenvolvidos: O que você precisa saber” (ptBR)</li>
      	<li> “Preventing Mother-to-Child Transmission of HIV/AIDS in Developing Countries: What You Need to Know”(en). “Prevenção
      à transmissão do HIV/AIDS de Mãe-para-Filho em Países em Desenvolvimento: O que você precisa saber” (ptBR)</li>
      	<li> “Why EVERY Person Should Be Tested for HIV When They Visit the Doctor” (en). “Why EVERY Person Should Be Tested for
      HIV When They Visit the Doctor” (ptBR)</li>
      	<li> “Wash Your Hands to Keep Yourself and Others Healthy: Recommendations for the Developed World.”(en). “Wash Your Hands
      to Keep Yourself and Others Healthy: Recommendations for the Developed World.” (ptBR)</li>
      	<li> “Wash Your Hands to Keep Yourself and Others Healthy: Recommendations for the Developing World.”(en). “Lave Suas Mãos
      para Preservar a Sua Saúde e a dos Outros: Recomendações para o Mundo em Desenvolvimento.”(ptBR)</li>
      	<li> “Preventing Waterborne Illnesses – the Major Cause of Death in Developing Countries” (en). “Prevenindo Doenças de Veiculação
      Hídrica – a maior causa de morte em países em desenvolvimento”(ptBR)</li>
      	<li> "Preventing Sexual Transmission of HIV: What You Need to Know"(en). Prevenção de Transmissão Sexual do HIV: O que você
      precisa saber”(ptBR)</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
      	<li> <strong>SHARE-INFORMATION</strong> - (<strong>página compartilhada)</strong></li>
      </ul>
      In this page there is a space for share information, exchanging experiences, expressions and more.
      <ul>
      	<li><strong>REVISIONS
      </strong></li>
      </ul>
      Text revisions in portuguese languages of tecnical genre, computational area - internet, for Bugzilla - AMO ( <a href="http://addons.mozilla.org/"
      target="_blank">addons.mozilla.org</a> )  site  <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/pt-BR/firefox/" target="_blank">https://addons.mozilla.org/pt<wbr></wbr>-BR/firefox.</a>
      , it refers to a first pt-BR version, and evaluations and feedback for this work will be always wellcome. The related docs
      are setting in <a href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=380221" target="_blank">https://bugzilla.mozilla.org<wbr></wbr>/show_bug.cgi?id=380221</a>.
      A text only will be completed by the help of the reader.<br/><br/><strong>Portuguese Languages: Text Comprehension</strong><br/><br/>Article
      about text comprehension in portuguese languages. In this article I followed, amoung other theories, the theoretical presuppositions
      of Tesnière, french linguist, Eléments de syntaxe structurale. The importance of the verbs for the better text comprehension.
      See the article <a href="http://gloria.taboca.com/dokuwiki/doku.php?id=start_languages:text_comprehension_1:ptbr" title="Text_comprehension
      ">Text Comprehension - portuguese language. </a>
      <p class="post" id="post-15">&nbsp;</p>
      <p class="post" id="post-16"><small> <!-- by admin --></small></p>]]>
   </content>
</article>