<?xml version="1.0" ?> <article xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
   <header>
      <title>Real and Imaginary - literature page</title>
      <categories>
         <category_item>literature</category_item>
      </categories>
   </header>
   <content><![CDATA[Tribute to José Saramago - prize novel of literature<br/><br/><img src="http://bp3.blogger.com/_ltdBOPpizaQ/RxiMMvx_BrI/AAAAAAAAAGA/KZTx82KYgJo/s1600/Image6.jpg"
      alt="[Image6.jpg]" border="0" /><br/><br/>The <strong>Convent's Memorial</strong><br/><br/><a href="http://bp2.blogger.com/_ltdBOPpizaQ/RnDP7DPEf5I/AAAAAAAAAAU/-x6_QBTLDGw/s1600-h/PC-IMG_0174.JPG"
      onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}"> </a>It was once a King who did the promise of lifting
      a convent in Mafra.
      It was once the people who built this convent.
      It was once an one-armed soldier and a woman who had powers.
      It was once a priest who wanted to fly and it died hurt.
      It was once. ”
      in Memorial of the Convent, 22nd ed., Lisbon, Publishing Way, 1994.<br/><br/>JOSÉ SARAMAGO<br/><br/>The most known writer
      of the Portuguese contemporary literature. His tragetory marks aspects from the Middle Age until until the  contemporary conflicts
      of the urban man. The domination and the political manipulation provokes deep reflections . Memorial of the Convent reports
      what the history did not count. Facts in the life of D.João V, Dna Maria Ana Josefa in counterpoint with the construction
      of a convent in Mafra. (..) Oh .. the love of Blimunda and Baltazar, nothing similar with it of the King and of the Queen.<br/><br/>“
      The water pitcher is waiting for the fountain ” idea what it has to do with a queen precise who to give a son to a king. There
      are priests inquizitores, typhoid fever, louse in the bed, and more... - extracted scenes of the background for the extreme
      skill of the writer of composing the scenery, that besides satisfying the expectations of the reader, lets them to compose
      the history.<br/><br/>It is real also:<br/><br/>a teacher called Álvaro Maia who lets all  pupils to fall in love with Portuguese
      Literature. With him, you make a tour in the space,  you like the scenes, you incorporate the characters, you enjoy yourself
      and  become clarefull yet!
      in Memorial do Convento, 22ª ed., Lisboa, Editorial Caminho, 1994.<br/><br/>Thanks, Álvaro!]]>
   </content>
</article>